Elsie Clews Parsons Papers 1835-1944 Mss.Ms.Coll.29
American Philosophical Society
- Elsie Clews Parsons Papers II, 1898-1937
  - Series I. Professional Correspondence, 1898-1937
    - Weiant, C.W., 1935 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Wheeler, Howard T., 1930; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
      - Espinosa, Aurelio M. (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Wheelwright, Mary C., 1935 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - White, Amelia [Elizabeth?], 1923 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - White, Leslie A., 1927-1941; 4 items (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - White, Leslie A. (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
      -See also Ser.VI, White, Leslie
      - Folder #1, [1927?]- Jun. 1930 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
      - Folder #2, Jul. 1930-31 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
      - Folder #3, 1932-33 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
      - Folder #4, 1934-37; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Whitman, A., 1921? (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Whooley, Mary, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Whorf, Benjamin L., 1933; 1935 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Wiley, Louis, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Williams, William, 1934 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Wilson, G.R., 1926; 1931 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Winters, John D., 1912 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Winthrop, B., 1912 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Wisdom, Charles, 1935 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Wisdom, Charles - Mss. - "Mem. from the Chorti of Eastern Guatemala", [ca. 1935?] (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
      -See Ser.IV, Chorti - Notes [taken by Charles Wisdom]
    - Wissler, Clark, 1918-22 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Woman's City Club (Boston, Mass.), 1921? (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Woman's Forum, 1916 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Women's Trade Union League, 1917 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Women's University Club (New York City), 1909 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
      -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Realty Company of the Women's University Club
    - Wood, Charles W. (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
      -See Ser.I, Sunday World
    - Wood, L. Hollingsworth (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
      -See Ser.I, American League to Limit Armaments
    - Wood, M.R., 1905? (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Woodall, N.F. - Mss. - "Old Signs in Alabama", 1930 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Woodson, Carter G., 1926-1927; 2 items (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Woodson, Carter G., 1934 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Woodward, Dorothy, 1933 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Woolston, Florence Guy - Mss. - "Marriage Customs and Taboos Among the Early Heterodites", [1919?] (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
      -See Ser.VII, "Marriage Customs Among the..."
    - Work, Monroe N., 1919 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
      -See Ser.IV, [African Proverbs]
    - Wyman, Leland C., 1936 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Yale Review, 1915 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Young, George (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
      - Folder #1, 1909-11 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
      - Folder #2, 1912 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
      - Folder #3, 1913-33; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Yves-Guyot, [?], 1919 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Zingg, Robert M., 1934-36; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Zoro, Angèlica Q. de, 1931-32; 1935 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
      in Spanish
    - Zuraik, Philip, 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
    - Unidentified, 1926-1936; 2 items (Box Papers-II Series-I: 8)
  - Series II. Personal Correspondence, 1882-1941; 1965
    - Abbott, Holken, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
      includes letters from family members, childhood friends, domestic help, and people with whom Parsons had primarily social relations. There is extensive correspondence with her husband, Herbert, and her son, John, both of which contain interesting information on herfield work in the Southwest and in Mexico. Series II is arranged alphabetically by correspondent and then chronologically within each file.
    - Adams, F.C., 1888; 1890; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Adams, Lilian, 1890; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Adams, Marion H., 1886; 1888; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Aldrich, Chester Holmes, 1906?; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Aldrich, Nelson W., n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Allison, W.B., 1906; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Andersen, Andreas, 1901 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Anderson, Sarah E., 1912-13 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Company, 1920 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Baker, George Bramwell, 1929-30 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Banks, Lucette, 1885-90; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Bannard, Otto T., n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - F.A. Bartlett Tree Expert Co., 1932-33; 1941 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
      -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Bartlett Tree Expert Co.
    - Belknap, Alice, 1882-90; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Bend, Beatrice, 1890? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Bennet, William S., 1906-11 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Berberich, Peter, 1936 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Berndt, Charles, 1914-27 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Blake, George Baty, 1909? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Boggs, Miss, 1901 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Boit[?], John, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Boney[?], P., n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Borden, Alfred, 1914 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Borden, Effie Brooks, 1888; 1890; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Borden, Leonora, 1888-90; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Bower, Anna E., 1884-89; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Boynton, Stanley C., 1934-35 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Brice, M., n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Bright, Leslie, 1890; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Brown, Caroline, 1938; 1965 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
      - Parsons, Fanny (Mrs. John) (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Brownell, Matilda, 1906?; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Buker, Lou C., 1890 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Bull, Harry A., n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Burden, Evelyn B., 1889; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Bureau for the Requirements of Social Life, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Burns, Gerald R., 1930 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Burton, T.E., 1907; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Busch, Bella C., 1887 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Butler, Lawrence, 1901 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Cameron, Anne F., 1890? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Camp ChocC3rua, 1889 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Carmody, Mary J., 1906-36 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Chappell, Walter F., 1901 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Church, Ulina Estelle, 1908 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Clews, Henry, Jr., 1885-1930; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
      brother
      -See also Ser.VI, Clews, Henry, Jr.
    - Clews, Henry, Sr., 1888-1921; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
      father
    - Clews, Henry, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
      nephew
    - Clews, James B., 1920-28 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Clews, Lucy Madison Worthington (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
      mother
      -See also Ser.II, Clews, Robert Bower
      - Folder #1, 1887-1909 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
      - Folder #2, 1910-35; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Clews, Robert Bower, 1890? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
      - Clews, Lucy Madison Worthington (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Clews Family - Genealogy, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Clotilde, L.M., n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Cohn, Sigmund, 1890? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Collins, Kathleen, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Colton, Bertha, 1888-90 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Cooley, Alford W., 1909-11 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Crane, W.M., 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Culberton, Louise, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Cushing, Howard G., 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Cushing, Lily D., n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 1)
    - Davies, Julien T., 1888 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - de Koven, Hana F. (Mrs. Reginald), 1936 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Dennett, Elizabeth, 1914? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Dewey, George, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Dexter, Josephine, 1894 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Dexter, Samuel (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
      - Folder #1, 1893-94; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
      - Folder #2, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
      - Folder #3, 1893-94; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
        letters from ECP silk purse
      - Folder #4, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Dillard, Calvin, 1913-14 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Drury, Samuel S., 1917 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Durand, Mortimer, Sir (and Lady) (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Durham, Jesse L., 1905 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Early, Mary, 1910 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Eckerman[?], Elizabeth S.M., 1917-18 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Eddy, Marie Seymour, 1890? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Edgar, Mary N., 1890? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Emery, Henry C., n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Erlandsen, Clarita K. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Fawcett de Cappeti, Laura, 1890 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Fearing, George R., 1890 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Fish, Lillie, 1889 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Fisher, Irving, 1908 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Foster, Murphy J., 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Fowler, Edward M., 1890? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Fowler, Louise M., 1890? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Francfort, Lena (Mrs. J.), 1906-11 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Frankel, Rose, 1932 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Fritsche, H., 1889 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Gedon, Anna, 1919 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Gerard, James W., 1889; 1935 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Greenough, J.T., 1890? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Griscom, Else, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Grondahl, Edla, 1930 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Hackett, C.F., 1914 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Hammond, Emily (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Hansbrough, H.C., n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Harding, Jewell C., 1921-25 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Harriman, Mary, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Hasking, Tom, 1901 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Hawxhurst, George W., 1911 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Heather II (Ship), 1912 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
      -See also Ser.I, Day, Clarence, 24 Jan. 1912
    - Henderson, Nathalie, 1911 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Herrick, Robert (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
      -See Ser.IX, Pajarito Ranch, N.M.
    - Herrick, Robert - Mss. - "A Feline World", 1929 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
      page proof; inscribed "To E.C.P." under title
    - Herter, Christian A., 1908-09 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Hindle[?], Jim (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Hirst, Francis W., 1908 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Hoar, R., 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Howard, Mrs., 1934 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Idle, Henry, 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Irving, Teresa, 1928 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Jenkins, Edwin, 1920 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Johnson, Jennie, 1919 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Joy, Walter T., 1935 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Joyce, Alden P., 1928-29 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Kearny, Thomas, 1890? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Kemp, Kate, 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Kennedy, John Drummond (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
      son-in-law
    - Kimball, Madeleine, 1925 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Kingman, John J., 1935 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Kirk, Adelaide C., 1920 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Knollwood Cemetery, 1910 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Kuhn, Laura, 1934 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Ladd, Elizabeth B., 1889 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Ladenburg, Emily, 1889 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - La Farge, Mabel, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - La Faye[?], H.B., n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Lawrence, A.T. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
      - Folder #1, 1888-90; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
      - Folder #2, 1890; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Lawrence, John, 1890 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 2)
    - Lee, Maud Stewart, 1889-90 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Lherbette, M., 1888 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Liggett, [?] W., 1901 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Light, Gertrude U., 1924-32 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - The Lincoln School of Teachers College (N.Y.C.), 1921 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Lockwood, Louise B., 1901 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Lodge, H.C., 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Lufis[?], L.L., 1887 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - McCormick, M., n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - McKay, J.H., n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - MacLeay, Luena B., 1919 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Maddell, Laura A., 1909 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Madeira, Lucy, 1909 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Manhattan Storage & Warehouse Co., 1929-32 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Marmon, R.O., 1931 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Matsuka, Mrs., 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Mijarda[?], B., n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Millard, M.W., 1889-90; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Millett, F.D., 1914? (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Morgan, E.P., n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Morgan, Helen, ca. 1901 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Morris, Arthur, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Nagle, Anne, 1935 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
      -See also Ser.X, Corr. - Nagle, Anne
    - Nearing, Scott, 1917 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Nechida, Masa, 1911 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Noble, Raymond Hull, 1914 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Osharu, L.P., n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Pagenstecher, Misses, 1886 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Parsons, Bertha Brush, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Parsons, Constance, 1901; 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Parsons, Elsie (Lissa) (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
      daughter
      -See also Ser.II, Young, J.H.
      -See also Ser.VI, Kennedy, Elsie (Lissa) Parsons
      -See also Ser.VII, [Journal of Lissa's Health and Growth]
      - Folder #1, 1909-12 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
      - Folder #2a, 1915-31 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
      - Folder #2b, 1932-35 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
      - Folder #3, n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
    - Parsons, Fanny W. (Mrs. John E.), 1940; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
      daughter-in-law
      -See also Ser.II, Brown, Caroline
    - Parsons, Herbert (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
      husband
      -See also Ser.VI, Parsons, Herbert
      - Folder #1, 1891; 1896 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
      - Folder #2, 1897 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
      - Folder #3, 1898 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
      - Folder #4a, Jan.-Aug. 1899 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
      - Folder #4b, Sep.-Dec. 1899; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
      - Folder #5a, Jan.-Jul. 1900 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
      - Folder #5b, Aug.-Dec. 1900 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
      - Folder #6, 1901 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
      - Folder #7, 1902 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 3)
      - Folder #8, 1903 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 4)
      - Folder #9a, Jan.-Jun. 1904 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 4)
      - Folder #9b, Jul.-Dec. 1904 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 4)
      - Folder #10, Feb.-Sep. 1905 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 4)
      - Folder #11, Oct.-Dec. 1905 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 4)
      - Folder #12, Jan.-Jun. 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 4)
      - Folder #13, Jul. 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 4)
      - Folder #14, Aug. 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 4)
      - Folder #15, Sep. 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 4)
      - Folder #16a, 1-15 Oct. 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 4)
      - Folder #16b, 16-31 Oct. 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 4)
      - Folder #17, Nov. 1906 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 4)
      - Folder #18, Jan.-Feb. 1907 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 4)
      - Folder #19, Mar. 1907 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 4)
      - Folder #20, Apr. 1907 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 4)
      - Folder #21, May-Jun. 1907 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 5)
      - Folder #22, Jul. 1907 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 5)
      - Folder #23, Sep. 1907 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 5)
      - Folder #24, Oct. 1907 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 5)
      - Folder #25, Jan.-Apr. 1908 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 5)
      - Folder #26, Jun. 1908 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 5)
      - Folder #27, Jul. 1908 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 5)
      - Folder #28, Aug. 1908 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 5)
      - Folder #29a, 1-9 Sep. 1908 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 5)
      - Folder #29b, 16-30 Sep. 1908 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 5)
      - Folder #30, Oct. 1908 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 5)
      - Folder #31, Nov.-Dec. 1908 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 5)
      - Folder #32, Mar.-May 1909 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 5)
      - Folder #33, Jun. 1909 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 5)
      - Folder #34, Jul. 1909 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 5)
      - Folder #35, Aug. 1909 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 5)
      - Folder #36, Sep. 1909 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 5)
      - Folder #37, Nov. 1909 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 5)
      - Folder #38, Feb.-May 1910 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 6)
      - Folder #39, Jun. 1910 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 6)
      - Folder #40, Jul.-Aug. 1910 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 6)
      - Folder #41, Sep. 1910 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 6)
      - Folder #42, Oct. 1910 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 6)
      - Folder #43, Nov.-Dec. 1910 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 6)
      - Folder #44, Feb.-Mar. 1911 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 6)
      - Folder #45, Apr. 1911 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 6)
      - Folder #46, May 1911 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 6)
      - Folder #47, Jun. 1911 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 6)
      - Folder #48, Jul. 1911 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 6)
      - Folder #49, Aug. 1911 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 6)
      - Folder #50, Sep. 1911 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 6)
      - Folder #51, Oct. 1911 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 6)
      - Folder #52, Nov.-Dec. 1911 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 6)
      - Folder #53, Jan.-May 1912 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 7)
      - Folder #54, Jun.-Jul. 1912 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 7)
      - Folder #55, Aug. 1912 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 7)
      - Folder #56, Sep.-Dec. 1912 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 7)
      - Folder #57, Jan.-Feb. 1913 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 7)
      - Folder #58, Apr.-Jun. 1913 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 7)
      - Folder #59, Jul.-Aug. 1913 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 7)
      - Folder #60, Sep.-Oct. 1913 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 7)
      - Folder #61, Nov.-Dec. 1913 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 7)
      - Folder #62, Jan.-Jun. 1914 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 7)
      - Folder #63, Jul.-Aug. 1914 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 7)
      - Folder #64, Sep. 1914 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 7)
      - Folder #65, Oct.-Dec. 1914 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 7)
      - Folder #66, Jan.-Jun. 1915 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 7)
      - Folder #67, Jul.-Sep. 1915 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 7)
      - Folder #68, Oct.-Dec. 1915 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 7)
      - Folder #69, Feb.-May 1916 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 8)
      - Folder #70, Jun.-Aug. 1916 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 8)
      - Folder #71, Sep.-Dec. 1916 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 8)
      - Folder #72, Jan.-May 1917 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 8)
      - Folder #73, Jun.-Jul. 1917 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 8)
      - Folder #74, Aug.-Sep. 1917 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 8)
      - Folder #75, Oct.-Dec. 1917 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 8)
      - Folder #76, Jan.-Feb. 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 8)
      - Folder #77, Mar.-Apr. 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 8)
      - Folder #78, May-Jun. 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 8)
      - Folder #79, Jul.-Sep. 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 8)
      - Folder #80, Oct. 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 8)
      - Folder #81, Nov. 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 8)
      - Folder #82, Dec. 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 8)
      - Folder #83, Jan. 1919 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 8)
      - Folder #84, Feb. 1919 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 8)
      - Folder #85, May-Jul. 1919 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 8)
      - Folder #86, Aug.-Dec. 1919 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 8)
      - Folder #87, Feb.-Jul 1920 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      - Folder #88, Aug.-Oct. 1920 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      - Folder #89, Nov.-Dec. 1920 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
        - True, Clara D. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      - Folder #90, Mar.-Jul. 1921 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      - Folder #91, Aug.-Nov. 1921 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      - Folder #92, 1922 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      - Folder #93, 1923 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      - Folder #94, 1924 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      - Folder #95, 1925; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
    - Parsons, Herbert - Power of Attorney, 1917 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
    - Parsons, Herbert, Jr., 1912; 1922-1935; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      son
    - Parsons, John E. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      father-in-law
    - Parsons, John E. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      - Folder #1, 1910-12 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      - Folder #2a, Jul.-Oct. 1916 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      - Folder #2b, Nov.-Dec. 1916 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      - Folder #3, 1917 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      - Folder #4, 1918 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      - Folder #5, 1919-20 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      - Folder #6, 1921 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
        - Parsons, McIlvaine (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      - Folder #7, 1922-23 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 9)
      - Folder #8, 1924-25 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
      - Folder #9, 1926 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
      - Folder #10, 1927-28 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
      - Folder #11, 1929-30 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
      - Folder #12, 1931 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
      - Folder #13, 1932 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
      - Folder #14, 1933-1934 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
      - Folder #15, 1935-36 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
        - Reichard, Gladys (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
      - Folder #16, 1937-41; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
        - Parsons, McIlvaine (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
    - Parsons, John E. - Poems, 1940-41; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
    - Parsons, John E. - "Talk Among the Tories" by B.R.T., 1937-39; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
    - Parsons, McIlvaine (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
      -See also Ser.II, Parsons, John E. [son], Folders #6 and #16
      - Folder #1, 1919-26 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
      - Folder #2, 1927-28 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
      - Folder #3, 1929-30 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
      - Folder #4, 1931-35 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
    - Parsons, McIlvaine - Daily News Editorials [Yale], 1931 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
    - Parsons, McIlvaine - Mss. - "Indian Life", 1925 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
    - Parsons, McIlvaine - Mss. - "An Interpretation of the Communist Theory of State", 1931 (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
    - Parsons, McIlvaine - Mss. - "Of Swimming in Duck Ponds", 16 Feb. [1931?] (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
    - Parsons, McIlvaine - Mss. - "Whitehead's Concept of Time", n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
    - Parsons, McIlvaine - Poems, 1928-29; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
    - Parsons, Mary, 1936; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)
    - Parsons family, 1901; n.d. (Box Papers-II Series-II: 10)